Francesco Fucci

Software Engineer

August 3, 1987

Benoitstraat 17, 5654BT Eindhoven

+31 6 25 35 53 30

§ fr.fucci

@ fr.fucci@hotmail.it

EU Citizenship

Social Network



Languages

■ Italian

English

■ French

Programming

- » C++ (11/14/17)
- » Julia
- " a
- » Python

Learning

» Rust

Working Experience

2021 - now Lead

Lead Software Engineer

ASML

Experience in leading team of 4-6 people. Prepare design documents, define tasks that team member can execute, perform code-reviews and design reviews. Individual contributor in different components of ASML archives. Contribution to the design of a library for tensor-based operations (i.e. einsum) using template-meta programming.

2019 – 2021 Software Design Engineer

ASML

- Development of calibration application for NXE machines (Python/C++)
- Development of a quadratic programming interior point solver in **Julia** and in **C++**.
- Refactoring of legacy C++ components to newer standards.
 Definition of the architecture of software components for new
 ASML machines, using C++ 11. Analyzed code performance
 with statistical benchmarks (i.e., Google Microbenchmark)

2015 - 2019 Senior Software Engineer

Critiware

- Contributed to the design of the plasma control system, which will be the control software system responsible of controlling part of the plant systems of the ITER Machine (https://www.iter.org). Design of the system using Model-Driven Design approaches from requirements analysis to structural solution. Contributed to the implementation of real-time software prototype in (C++14) on Linux RHEL 6.
- Development of tools to assess the tolerance to software errors, which is now used in production to assess Android OS low-level code using (C++11).
- Tools for the analysis of post-drive run for trains (Java, Eclipse RCP Dependency Injection Framework).
- Developed a DSL to aid developers to assess Python code.

2011 – 2012 Software Engineer

SESM

Toolchain tailoring automatic code generation of test code for ATC applications.

Education

Postgraduate Training

2013 – 2014 PhD Research Internship

EPFL

I contributed on the development of components for a platform for the automated analysis of systems code. I developed an interpreter in C++, which executes symbolic expressions. The project is available at the following address: S2E

Francesco Fucci

Software Engineer

About Me

I enjoy building systems and learning new things. Currently my favorite topics are modern programming languages, system design, quantitative methods. I worked in several domains from railways systems, fusion, and lithography machines.

Design Skills —

- » Agile Software Design: SOLID, Design Patterns
- » Numerical Optimization
- » Machine Learning
- » Deep-Learning
- » Operating Systems
- » Systems Design

Other Skills

- » MATLAB
- » Git
- > Jenkins
- » Boost
- » Tensoflow
- » Keras

Keywords

Agile

Collaboration

Team-oriented

Goal-oriented

Quick-learning AI

Academic

2012 – 2015 PhD Computer Engineering

UNINA

Thesis: Model-based verification of Operating Systems device drivers. In my thesis I explored different techniques for automatic verification of device drivers like runtime verification and symbolic execution.

2009 – 2011 Master Degree Computer Engineering

I developed an approach based on the reinforcement learning paradigm

with the aim of generating state driven workload, for fault injection

purposes.

2005 – 2008 Bachelor Degree Computer Engineering

During my B.Sc thesis i was involved in the creation of a tool for online monitoring of Linux kernel's part using an hypervisor based

architecture to detect hangs in device drivers.

Personal Projects

Match Matching-Engine in Rust. link

IEX feed Feed reader for TOPS IEX trading protocol. link

M-Opt A C + +20 framework to price options with Montecarlo method

(ongoing project). link

SLANG A DSL to specify contracts for device driver verification (C++, Boost,

Java).

Talks

JuliaCon Towards Using Julia for RealTime applications at ASML

2022

C++Day Principles of algorithm design in STL

2019

Awards

2006–2007 Best Student Award

Best student of the of University of Napoli "Federico II" Computer

Engineering faculty.